# REETIK PATEL

(479) 385-1212
reetikp@gmail.com
www.reetikpatel.me
www.linkedin.com/in/reetik

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a full-stack engineer with a passion for creating **intuitive**, **research backed** user interfaces. The user always comes first! With over **9 years** of building **enterprise solutions**, I emphasize maintainability and efficiency in my work. I'm able to pick up new processes and tools very quickly. I've worked on projects from simple web pages to applications serving **millions of clients** and managing **billions of dollars** in transactions.

#### **SKILLS & TOOLS**

Typescript/Javascript	NextJS	Tailwind	Zeplin
React	Remix	User Experience (UX)	Azure
React Native	NodeJS	Sketch	Git
HTML   CSS   SASS	Vue	Figma	CI/CD
Kotlin / Java	Storybook	Adobe XD	

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### XEROSEC LLC

Software Engineer | Jan 2024 - May 2024

- Designed, built, and released new front-end for a script sharing platform using NX monorepo and component library documented with Storybook
- Integrated Oauth2 with Azure B2C
- Made CI/CD pipelines with Github Actions

#### BILL.COM / DIVVY

Software Engineer | Oct 2022 - Dec 2023

- Created new budget tools including policy management and import functionality for budget groups serving
   461,000 businesses controlling over \$4 billion in total payment volume (TPV)
- Greatly improved test coverage and code readability
- Worked on migrating legacy Javascript monorepo to new federated Typescript repositories

#### WALMART GLOBAL TECH

Software Engineer | Nov 2016 - Sept 2022

- Worked on a notification system for store emergency alerts such as inclement weather, active shooter situations, and COVID exposures
- Created an admin UI to manage an internal notification platform integrated into 200+ business-facing mobile applications
- Maintained the Apple code signing process for all internal iOS applications involving hundreds certificates and 600+ provisioning profiles
- Applied UX practices in documentation and example projects shared with thousands of associates
- Worked with the Al & Machine Learning team on a mobile application to improve data entry
- Contributed to NodeJS and Java Spring APIs
- Managed deployments to hybrid cloud infrastructure hosted on-prem and in Azure
- Applied CI/CD pipelines to streamline numerous support processes using Jenkins

#### **DESIGN PICKLE**

Software Engineer | Sept 2024 - Current

- Migrated web app from legacy Rails-served React app to new **Remix** system
- Improved test coverage
- Set up CI/CD workflow to publish Storybook implementations of both legacy and new applications
- Released new project management features as well as numerous bug fixes

## EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

### UNIVERSITY OF ARKANSAS

Bachelor of Arts, Computer Science Minor in Management

NIELSEN NORMAN GROUP (NN/G)
UX MASTER CERTIFIED

Specialties in Interaction Design and UX Research